Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/roshaprajapa ti (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Python JavaScript SQL

Certifications

pandas Essential Training
AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate

Rosha Prajapati

Python Developer | AWS Certified Kathmandu

Summary

An experienced python developer with 5+ years of experience with expertise in enterprise applications, event-driven applications, Microservices, data scrapping, crawling, data processing, data visualization, statistical analysis, computing, ml utilization, AWS services like ec2, lambda, S3, SQS etc.

Experience

Verisk

Software Engineer September 2021 - Present (11 months)

Kathmandu, Bāgmatī, Nepal

- Involved in the team of 7 in an analytics project that entails data processing, ml model utilization and statistical analysis among other software engineering tasks
- The role entails application development, data preprocessing, algorithm design and implementation, text mining models utilizations for analysis of insurance pdf documents
- Used tech stacks: Flask, Angular, MongoDB, AWS ec2, lambda, SQS, S3, Pandas, Numpy

Tekvortex

Software Engineer

November 2019 - September 2021 (1 year 11 months)

Kathmandu, Nepal

- Involved in a team of ten for a web content archiving platform as a contractor for Smarsh Inc.
- The archiving platform entailed a scaled web content crawling and processing engine, an in-house built scheduling system, a diversified archiving process, optimized searching, and exports on demand.
- Worked with technologies like tasks queuing and scheduling, batch processing, web-content proxying, searching, reporting, scripting etc.
- Contributed to converting the core monolithic application to numerous isolated distributed services with a centralized data store.

Page 1 of 2

- Deployed and maintained applications in on-premise dev and QA environments

Smart Solutions
Python Developer
November 2017 - January 2019 (1 year 3 months)
Kathmandu, Nepal

- Backend developer involved in development of application featuring data collection, aggregation and analysis.
- R&D contribution, Architecture brainstorming for solutions to application related problems
- Server-side/API development in Python, data visualization and analysis
- Involvement in product release and deployment

3Hammers Pvt. Ltd.
Web Developer
June 2016 - September 2017 (1 year 4 months)
Kathmandu, Nepal

- Worked in a web development team for an E-commerce project.
- Contributed in new features and enhanced the existing features using
- Python (django), jQuery and MySQL

Education

Tribhuvan University
Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer Engineering · (October 2013 - October 2017)

Little Angel's College 10 + 2, Science · (2011 - 2013)

Little Angels High School High School · (2010)